

## **Kodie Grantham**

Des Moines, Iowa

kodie.grantham@gmail.com

kodieg.com linkedin.com/in/kodie github.com/kodie

#### **Background**

Self-taught in all skills listed above. Over 17 years of personal computer and web development experience. Excellent ability to investigate, diagnose, and resolve all technical problems. Extremely quick learner with the desire to always be learning and broadening my knowledge while staying up to date with new technologies.

### Skills Languages

HTML(5), CSS(3), PHP, JavaScript, C#, XML, JSON, Shell, Visual Basic and a little Java.

#### **Tools/Frameworks**

Node.js, jQuery, Underscore.js, Grunt, Gulp.js, Bower, Composer, MySQL, MongoDB, and Meteor.

#### **Operating Systems**

Microsoft Windows, Linux, Google Android, and Apple macOS / iOS.

#### **Miscellaneous**

Wired and wireless networking, hardware (diagnoses, repair, and replacement), and electrical wiring.

## **Work Experience**



# Senior Product Engineer Happy Medium

March 2016 - Current

- Sole Engineer/Developer of product software and hardware.
- Development of web software using Meteor, NodeJS, Blaze, and MongoDB using programming languages such as HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, JSON, and Mustache.
- Development of Android-based firmware as well as web-based APIs for updates to software.
- Development of Wordpress managed, mobile-responsive websites.
- Development of custom, SHELL-based internal tools.
- On-site installation of digital signage hardware for clients.
- Management and maintenance of Linux-based web servers.
- API implementation for various uses such as payment gateways, file storage/access, and social media.
- Creation of custom CSS3 animations for web projects.
- Some minor work with Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator as well as Sketch.



#### Web Developer Webspec Design

June 2015 - March 2016

- Development of custom websites for clients using programming languages such as HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, PHP, JSON, and more.
- Working with designers to create custom, mobile responsive websites for clients.
- Development of custom internal tools for use by the development team to help make creating and launching websites more efficient.
- Development of custom web applications such as employee dashboards, coupon systems, airline tracking systems, etc.
- Development of custom mobile applications for both Android and Apple devices for clients.
- Converting Non-CMS websites over to WordPress, SASS, Gulp, Bower, and Composer.
- Making desktop-only websites mobile responsive.
- Transferring website files along with databases to different servers.
- Transferring DNS records for websites and changing A, CNAME, and MX records for domain names.
- Meeting with clients to discuss potential custom websites as well as working with Project Managers to come up with proposals for clients.
- Use of web development command-line production tools such as Gulp, Grunt, and Bower.



## Owner/Operator Five Fifteen Printing & Design

November 2013 - June 2015

- Started the business from the ground up.
- Made custom designs to be printed onto t-shirts for customers as well as prepping of designs for screen printing using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator.
- Screen printed t-shirts and other merchandise using a manual, 4color screen printing press.
- Mixed plastisol inks to create custom Pantone colors at the request of customers for printing.
- Coated screens with emulsion as well as exposed designs onto screens for printing.
- Handled all customer service, e-mails, quotes, invoicing, taxes, finances, equipment repair, and ordering of supplies.

# Download my resume in other formats at kodieg.com/resume

## **Work Experience (Continued)**



# Computer Repair Technician/Web Developer KodieG-PC Computer Solutions

April 2012 - June 2015

- Diagnosis and repair of any and all technical related problems for customers including but not limited to computer software and hardware, wired and wireless networking, and even troubleshooting of entertainment devices such as TVs, surround sound systems, gaming consoles, and smartphones.
- Custom web design and programming as well as web hosting for customers using a wide variety of tools and skills.

### **Projects**



### **GameRanger Account Switcher (GRAS)**

kodieg.com/projects/gras/
github.com/kodie/gameranger-account-switcher/

- A Windows desktop application developed in C#.
- A tool for the multiplayer gaming client known as GameRanger. It allows you to log out of a user and log in as a different one so that gamers who share a computer can use their own accounts rather than share one.
- Handles moving, renaming, and modifying GameRanger files.
- Checks for running GameRanger processes and closes them after prompting the user.
- Has had over 26,400 downloads since version 1.0 was released October 16th, 2010.



### **Gravity Forms Repeater Add-On (gfRepeater)**

kodieg.com/projects/gravityforms-repeater-add-on/github.com/kodie/gravityforms-repeater/wordpress.org/plugins/repeater-add-on-for-gravity-forms/

- A WordPress plugin add-on for Gravity Forms developed in PHP, JavaScript (jQuery), and CSS (SASS).
- Allows specified groups of fields to be repeated by the user.
- Hooks into WordPress and Gravity Forms filters.
- Extends existing JavaScript functions.
- Had had over 4,100 downloads since version 1.0 was released October 11th, 2015.